Guide to the Henry Ernest Sigerist Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1957 died (March 17)
Centaurus; Journal of World History; Medicine -- History; Medicine -- Study and teaching; Medicine -- United States; National health services -- Soviet Union; Public health -- Asia; Public health -- Soviet Union; Radicalism; World politics -- 1945-1989; World War, 1914-1918; Europe; Germany; Historians; Physicians; Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection; Barkan, Adolf, 1845-; Baudisch, Oskar; Baur, Marguerite Louise; Brown, Esther Lucile, 1898-; Brunn, Walter von, 1876-1952; Brunner, Conrad, 1859-1927; Buess, Heinrich, 1911-; Castiglioni, Arturo, 1874-1953; Chance, Burton, 1868-; Chesney, Alan M. (Alan Mason), 1888-1964; Clark, Charles Upson, 1875-1960; Corsini, Andrea, 1875-; Dalrymple-Champneys, W. (Weldon), 1892-1980; Dalsace, Jean Charles, 1893-; Dannemann, Friedrich, 1859-1936; Devrient, Wilhelm; Diepgen, Paul, 1878-1966; Drabkin, I. E. (Israel Edward), 1905-1965; Ebstein, Erich, 1880-1931; Edelstein, Ludwig, 1902-1965; Falk, Leslie A.; Fernández del Castillo, Francisco, 1864-1936; Fischer, Hans, 1892-1976; Fueter, Eduard, 1876-1928; Fulton, John F. (John Farquhar), 1899-1960; Fürrer-Proud, Millicent; Galdston, Iago, 1895-; Garrison, Fielding H. (Fielding Hudson), 1870-1935; Giesbrecht, Elisabeth; Gonzenbach, Willi von; Grmek, Mirko D. (Mirko Dražen), 1924-2000; Guthrie, Douglas, 1885-1975; Haberling, W. (Wilhelm), 1871-1940; Hellman, Lillian, 1905-1984; Herrlinger, Robert, 1914-1968; Herzig, Rudolf; Hess von Wyss, Jean Jacques, 1866-; Howald, Ernst, 1887-1967; Hume, Edward H. (Edward Hicks), 1876-1957; Hyman, Harold Thomas, 1894-; Izquierdo, José Joaquín, 1893-1974; Jörimann, Julius; Kahn, Eugen, 1887-; Kingsbury, John Adams, 1876-1956; Klebs, Arnold C. (Arnold Carl), 1870-1943; Koch, Richard; Kolle, Kurt, 1898-; Koudelka, Janet Brock; Larkey, Sanford V. (Sanford Vincent), 1898-; Lazaron, Morris S. (Morris Samuel), 1888-1979; Lazarus, Paul; Leake, Chauncey Depew, 1896-1978; Leibowitz, J. O. (Joshua Otto), 1895-; Leikind, Morris C. (Morris Cecil), 1905-1976; Lely, Marianne Bickel; Lendi, Jakob Ulrich; Licht, Sidney, 1907-1979; Long, Esmond R. (Esmond Ray), 1890-1979; López Sánchez, José, 1911-; Mackintosh, James M. (James Macalister), 1891-1966; Major, Ralph Hermon, 1884-; Martí-Ibáñez, Félix, 1915-1972; Matoušek, Miloslav, 1900-; Mayer, Claudius F., 1899-1988; McHenry, Lawrence C., 1929-; McKinney, Loren Carey, 1891-; Mehatā, Prāṇajīvana Māṇekacanda, 1892-1979; Meng, Heinrich, 1887-1972; Michaud, Louis; Mieli, Aldo, 1879-1950; Miller, Benjamin Frank, 1907-1971; Milt, Bernhard, 1896-1956; Mooser, Hermann, 1891-1971; Morris, J. N. (Jeremy Noah); Neuburger, Max, 1868-1955; Norpoth, Leo, 1901-; Oliver, John Rathbone, 1872-1943; Pagel, Walter, 1898-1983; Paradise, Jack Leon; Pavlov, Ivan Petrovich, 1849-1936; Paz-Soldán, Carlos Enrique, 1885-; Pelseneer, Jean, 1903-; Perry, Isabella H.; Roemer, Milton Irwin, 1916-2001; Rosen, George, 1910-1977; Rosenfeld, Leonard S.; Rump, Hedwig Wiskermann; Sallenbach-Keller, Lily, 1891-; Sand, René, 1877-1953; Sarton, George, 1884-1956; Saussure, Raymond de, 1894-1971; Schinz, Hans R. (Hans Rudolf), 1891-; Schullian, Dorothy M. (Dorothy May), 1906-1989; Schultz, Friedrich Heinrich Adolf, 1867-; Schumann, Henry; Sheps, Cecil G. (Cecil George), 1913-2004; Shryock, Richard Harrison, 1893-1972; Sigerist, Emma; Sigerist, Emmy; Sigerist, Erica; Sigerist, Henry E. (Henry Ernest), 1891-1957; Sigerist, William Bernard; Silberschmidt, Max, 1899-; Silver, George A., 1913-2005; Silverman, Charlotte; Singer, Charles, 1876-1960; Singer, Dorothea Waley, 1884-; Smith, Jessica, 1895-1983; Spector, Benjamin, 1893-1976; Štampar, Andrija, 1888-1958; Stanton, Madeline E. (Madeline Earle); Steuer, Robert O. (Robert Otto); Stevenson, Lloyd G., 1918-; Stroomann, Gerhard, 1887-1957; Sudhoff, Karl, 1853-1938; Tjomsland, Anne, 1880-; Underwood, E. Ashworth, 1899-1980; Urdang, George, 1882-1960; Vaillancourt, Emile, 1889-; Viets, Henry R. (Henry Rouse), 1890-1969; Vonwiller, Paul, 1885-1962; Waller, Erik, 1875-1955; Wehrli, Gustav Adolf; Weinerman, E. Richard (Edwin Richard), 1917-1970; Weisberger, Siegfried; Welch, William Henry, 1850-1934; Wenger, Alfred, 1932-; Wheeler, Helen W., 1910-; Wickersheimer, Ernest, 1880-1965; Zilboorg, Gregory, 1890-1959; Citadel Press; Europaverlag; Gesellschaft der Aerzte des Kantons Zürich; John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation; Johns Hopkins University; Johns Hopkins University. Institute of the History of Medicine; Karl-Marx-Universität Leipzig; Leo S. Olschki (Firm); London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine; Pestalozzi Foundation; Royal College of Physicians of London; Royal Society of Medicine (Great Britain); Schweizerische Landesbibliothek; Universität Zürich; University of London; Werden und Wirken Verlag; Women's International League for Peace and Freedom; World Health Organization; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Correspondence, 1897-(1913-1957)-1970; Series I; 12 linear feet (30 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  CORRESPONDENCE is arranged in seven sections: General, 1913-1925; General, 1931-1946; General, 1947-1957; Topical, 1947-1957; Family; Nora Sigerist Beeson; and Collected Letters. Each section is arranged alphabetically by writer except that the letters in the Topical section are alphabetical by subject. There are cross-references from the three General sections to the other sections of this series and to various locations in Series II. There are no cross-references from one General section to another.
  Folders with asterisks(*) contain ten or more items.
  - General, 1913-1925
    - Allbutt, T. Clifford, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General
      See also: box 3, folder 119-126
    - [Andel?], M. A. van, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - L'Art Ancien S.A., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bachmann, Albert, 1923, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Balzli, [Hans O.K.?], 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bamberg, Bibliothek, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Barkan, Adolf(*), 1922-1925, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Barth (Johann Ambrosius) Verlag, 1922-1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Barth (Otto Wilhelm) Verlag, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Baudisch, Oskar(*), 1915-1921, undated (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    - Baumann, Otto, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Baur, Marguerite(*), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Baur, Marguerite(*), 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Baurigir, Theodor and Nina, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bayerische Staatsbibliothek, 1920, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Berg, Victor, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bernhardt, O., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bernheim-Karrer, J., [1924-1925?] (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bernoulli, E[ugene?], 1923 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bibliothèque Nationale de Paris, 1919, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bilancioni, Guglielmo, 1923, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - [Binnschwiln?], M., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Binswanger, Eugen, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bircher, Max E., 1922 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bloch, Bruno, 1920-1925, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bose, Ann, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Briffault, Muriel, 1921, 1924, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Briffault, R., [1922-1924] (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Brunn, Walter von(*), 1922-1925 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Brunner, Conrad(*), 1917-1925, undated (Box 1, Folder 18-21)
    - Brustlein, Alfred, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Büsse, Elizabeth (Mrs. Otto), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      See also: box 3, folder 105-112
    - Buily, ____, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Capparoni, Pietro, 1923-1925 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Carbonelli, Giovanelli, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Castiglioni, Arturo(*), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      See also: box 2, folder 77
    - Castiglioni, Arturo(*), 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Chagliardi, ____, 1917, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Cloetta, M., 1923, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Clairmont, P[aul?], 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Comrie, John D., 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Corsini, Andrea, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Cumston, Charles G., 1922 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      See also: box 2, folder 66 See also: box 3, folder 119-126 See also: box 4, folder 129-136
    - Dannemann, Friedrich(*), 1923-1925 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Darmstaedter, Ernst, 1924-1925, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Diepgen, Paul, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Dobson, John Frederic, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Dorveaux, Paul, 1920-1923 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Dürck, Hermann, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Ebstein, Erich H.(*), 1920-1924 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Fischer, Ed., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Fischer, Ed., 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Fleisch, Alfred ("Caro"), 1921-1925, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Francis, William Willoughby, 1923, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Frey, Hedwig, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - [Furrer?], H., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Garrison, Fielding Hudson, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Geiser, ____, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Gesellschaft der Aerzte des Kantons Zürich, 1920-1925 (Box 1, Folder 38-39)
    - Giesbrecht, Elisabeth(*), 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Gruber, U. von, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Guinet, L., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Gÿory, [Tibor?](*), 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Haberling, Wilhelm(*), 1922-1925, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Haberling, ____ (Mrs. Wilhelm), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Häne, J., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Haggenmacher, Ernst, [1924?] (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Harrassowitz, Otto, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Hauff, Bruno, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Haustein, Friedel, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Hedinger, E., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Heitz, Fritz, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Hemmeter, John C., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Hemmi-Bezzola, J., 1922 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Henking, Anna ("Anneli"), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Henking, Emma Bollinger (Mrs. Karl), 1924 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Herzig, Rudolf(*), 1923-1925, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Hess, Jean-Jacques(*), 1919-1925, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Hess, W., 1922 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Hess, ____, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - [Hildebrand?], ____, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - [Hirsch-Faber, F.?](Mrs. Alfred Hirsch), 1925 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Hochschulkorrespondenz, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Hochuli, A., 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Hoegger, B., 1921, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Hoenisch, E., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Hofman, G., 1925 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Hollenweger, E., 1925 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Hommel, Eherhard, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - [Honigman?], ____, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Hottinger, Paul, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Hotz, A., 1924 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Howald, Annie, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Howald, Ernst(*), 1915-1917 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Howald Ernst(*), 1918-1925 (Box 2, Folder 58-59)
    - Huber, Amin, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Hübscher, ____, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - [Humbelin?], A., 1922 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Idiotikon, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Internationaal Antiquariaat, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Jacky, Wilhelm, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Jörimann, Julius, 1923-1925 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Jörimann-Elwert, J., 1924 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Jones, Robert, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Jost, Ernst, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Karrer, P., 1924 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Klebs, Arnold C.(*), 1919-1920 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Klebs, Arnold C.(*), 1921-1923 (Box 2, Folder 67-70)
    - Klebs, Arnold C.(*), 1924-1925, undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
      See also: box 3, folder 116-117 See also: box 3, folder 119-126 See also: box 4, folder 129-136
    - Koch, Richard, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Lachs, Johann, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Lane, [John Edward?], 1924 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Lauener, Willy, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Lehrmann, Paul, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Leisinger, Hermann(*), 1923-1925 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Lejeune, Fritz, 1922-1925 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Lendi, Jakob Ulrich(*), 1922-1925, undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Leuch, Otto, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Lier (R.) & Co.(*), 1923 January-May (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Lier (R.) & Co.(*), 1923 June-Dec, 1924 January-Aug, 1924 September-1925, undated (Box 2, Folder 78-80)
    - Lippmann, Eduard von, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Lucca, Biblioteca Governativa di, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Luscher, ____, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Lustenberger, F., 1923-1925 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Maar, Vilhelm, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Maier, [Hans W.], 1922, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Marolt, Alfred, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Martin, ____, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Marzell, [Heinrich?], 1923 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Mayrhofer, B[ernhard?], 1925 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Medical Life
      See: box 3, folder 101
    - Meiss, Hans, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Meusser, Hermann, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Meyenburg, [H.?] von, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Meyer, Ernst, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - [Meyerhof, Max?], 1922 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Meyer's Möbeltransportgeschäft, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Meyer-Steineg, Theodor, 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Michaud, Louis, 1923-1925 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Mieli, Aldo, 1922-1925 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Milt, Bernhard, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Minns, Ellis, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Mounier, E., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Monumenta Medica
      See: box 1, folder 24
      See: box 4, folder 162
      See: box 1, folder 43
      See: box 2, folder 66
      See: box 2, folder 77
      See: box 3, folder 116-117
      See: box 3, folder 119-126
      See: box 4, folder 129-136
    - Morgenthaler, Walter, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Morin, Charles, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Moynihan, Berkeley, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Müller, Albert, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Müller, Erich, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Müller, [H.?], 1921-1923 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Müller, Hermann, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Müller, Reinhold F. G., 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Munich, University of
      See: box 1, folder 41 See: box 3, folder 103 See: box 3, folder 104
    - Muralt, Wilhelm von, 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Nachmanson, Ernst, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Neuburger, Max(*), 1921-1925 (Box 3, Folder 97)
      See also: box 2, folder 66 See also: box 3, folder 119-126
    - Neue Zürcher Zeitung, undated (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Peyer, [Bernhard?], 1921, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Proskauer, Curt, 1922, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Quervain, F. de, 1923-1925 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Reddy, D.V. Subba
      See: box 6, folder 231
    - Robinson, Victor, 1924-1925 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Rodt, Walther E. von, 1922-1925 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Rolleston, Humphrey, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Rychuer, Max, 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Sandoz, Chemische Fabrik vormals, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Sauerbruch, [Ada?] (Mrs. Ferdinand), 1924 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Sauerbruch, Ferdinand, 1924-1925 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Scherman, L., 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Schinz, Dori Strehin (Mrs. Hans Rudolf)
      See: box 3, folder 105-112
    - Schinz, Hans Rudolf(*), 1913-1924 (Box 3, Folder 105-112)
    - Schinz, Hans Rudolf(*), 1925, undated (Box 3, Folder 113)
      See also: box 14, folder 527
    - Schoellhorn, Hans and Marguerite, undated (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Schrödinger, ____, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Seldwyla Verlag, 1923-1924, undated (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Senn, George(*), 1922-1925 (Box 3, Folder 116-117)
    - Silberschmidt, Max(*), 1923, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Singer, Charles(*), 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Singer, Charles(*), 1922-1924 (Box 3, Folder 119-126)
    - Singer, Charles(*), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 127)
      See also: box 1, folder 8 See also: box 2, folder 66 See also: box 31, folder 2
    - Singer, Dorothea Waley (Mrs. Charles), 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Sticker, Georg, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Strohl, J[ohannes E. F.?], 1922-1925 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Sudhoff, Karl(*), 1917-1924 (Box 4, Folder 129-136)
    - Sudhoff, Karl(*), 1925, undated (Box 4, Folder 137)
      See also: box 4, folder 160 See also: box 4, folder 162 See also: box 1, folder 33 See also: box 1, folder 42 See also: box 2, folder 66 See also: box 18, folder 676 See also: box 30, folder 979
    - Sudhoff, Walther, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Sudhoff festschrift
      See: box 1, folder 21 See: box 4, folder 162 See: box 1, folder 30 See: box 5, folder 167 See: box 1, folder 33 See: box 5, folder 174 See: box 1, folder 37 See: E. Hoenisch See: box 2, folder 63 See: box 2, folder 66 See: box 2, folder 73 See: box 2, folder 81 See: box 6, folder 206 See: box 3, folder 97 See: box 18, folder 676 See: box 3, folder 102 See: box 3, folder 115 See: box 3, folder 116-117 See: box 3, folder 119-126 See: box 3, folder 128 See: box 4, folder 137 See: box 4, folder 142
    - Tsirch, A., 1923 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Walthan, M., 1921, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Weber, Hellmut H., 1920-1924 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - [Webrand?], ____
      See: ____, [Hildebrand?]
    - Wehrli, Gustav(*), 1917-1925 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Wehrli, ____ (Mrs. Gustav), 1921 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Werner, Hans, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Wickersheimer, Ernst(*), 1921-1925 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Wolff (Kurt) Verlag, 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Zaunick, Rudolph, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Zurich, University of
      See: box 36, folder 84
    - Unidentified, 1920-1925, undated (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - General, 1931-1946
    - Ad-American C (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - American L-Az (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Achelis, Johann Daniel, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Ackerknecht, Erwin H.(*), 1941-1945 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Afro-American, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Allen (George) & Unwin, Ltd., 1931 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - American Council on Soviet Relations, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Ames, Joseph S., 1931-1934 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Ba-Be (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Bi-Bz (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Bilikiewicz, Tadeusz, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Boise, Margaret Galt, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Boston, Hope Trebing(*), 1935 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Boston, Hope Trebing(*), 1936-1941 July-Aug, 1944, undated (Box 4, Folder 155-158)
    - Bowman, Isaiah, 1939-1947, undated (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Brodel, Elisabeth (Mrs.), 1932 (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Brunn, Walter von, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - C (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - Castiglioni, Arturo, 1933, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - Chesney, Alan Mason(*), 1931-1933, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 163)
      See also: box 27, folder 934
    - Cumberland Valley Medical Society, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 164)
    - Cushing, Harvey, 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - D (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Diepgen, Paul, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Edelstein, Ludwig(*), 1933-1945 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - F (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - Falk, Joy Hume (Mrs. Leslie Alan), 1942 (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - Forel, Oscar L., 1939 (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - Fueter, Eduard, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - Fulton, John F.(*), 1931-1932, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - G (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - Galdston, Iago, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 174)
    - Garrison, Fielding Hudson(*), 1931-1932 June (Box 5, Folder 174)
      - E (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Garrison, Fielding Hudson(*), 1932 July-1934, undated (Box 5, Folder 175)
    - Ghosh, Kamala(*), 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 176)
    - Gillman, Joseph, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - Goucher College(*), 1931-1934 (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - Graham, Helen ("Brookie")(*) (Box 5, Folder 178)
    - (Mrs. William Henry), 1933-1935, undated (Box 5, Folder 178)
    - Greenbelt Health Association, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - Gregg, Alan, 1933, 1939, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - Grodka, Sonia, 1943-1944, undated (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Guardian
      See: box 6, folder 218
    - Guggenheim (John Simon) Memorial Foundation, 1931-1932, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - H, 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Hauff, Bruno(*), 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Hume, Edward Hicks, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - I (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - Illing, Wolfram, 1932, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - J (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - Jauniaux, Arthur, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - Johns Hopkins University (miscellaneous)(*), 1941-1945 (Box 5, Folder 189)
      See also: box 4, folder 150 See also: box 4, folder 159 See also: box 5, folder 163 See also: box 37, folder 101-107
    - K (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - Kaiserlich Deutsche Akademie der Naturforscher zu Halle, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - Kast, Ludwig(*), 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 192)
    - Klebs, Arnold Carl, 1932-1934, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - Klebs, Harriet (Mrs. Arnold Carl), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1933 (Box 5, Folder 194)
    - Kontzias, Helen T., 1942, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - Koudelka, Janet (Mrs. Karl)
      See: box 6, folder 206
    - L (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - Landsberg, Eva, 1936-1941 (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - Larkey, Sanford V.(*), 1931-1932, undated (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - Leake, Chauncey D.(*), 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - Lehmanns (J. F.) Verlag(*), 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - Leipzig City Council, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - Leslie, Robert L., 1946 (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - M (Box 5, Folder 201)
    - Mackenzie, Cosmo, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - Mackenzie, Julia (Mrs. Cosmo), 1941 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - Maryland Society for the Promotion of This and That, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 203)
    - Matschoss, E., 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 204)
    - Mayer, Claudius Frank(*), 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 204)
    - Meyer, Adolf, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 205)
    - Micheli, Louis H., 1933 (Box 6, Folder 205)
    - Mieli-Miller (Box 6, Folder 206)
      - Mieli, Aldo, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 206)
      - Miller, Genevieve(*), 1938-1941 July (Box 6, Folder 206)
    - Miller, Genevieve(*), 1941 August (Box 6, Folder 207)
    - Miller, Genevieve (with Janet Koudelka), 1942 (Box 6, Folder 208)
    - N (Box 6, Folder 209)
    - Neuberger, Max, 1932, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 210)
    - Neue Blatter für den Sozialismus, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 210)
    - Norton, Hester (Mrs. W. W.?), 1932 (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - Norton (W. W.) & Company, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - O (Box 6, Folder 212)
    - Oliver, John Rathbone(*), 1931-1937, undated (Box 6, Folder 213)
    - P (Box 6, Folder 214)
    - Pagel, Walter, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 215)
    - Panofsky, Erwin, 1933, undated (Box 6, Folder 215)
    - Pearl, Raymond, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 216)
      See also: box 5, folder 203
    - R (Box 6, Folder 217)
    - Radford, Betty, 1940-1945 (Box 6, Folder 218)
    - Raymond, Marcel, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 219)
    - Reddy, D. V. Subba
    - Robinson, George Canby, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 219)
    - Rockefeller Foundation
      See: box 13, folder 490
    - Roemer, Milton I.(*), 1939-1946 (Box 6, Folder 220)
    - Rosen, George, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 221)
    - Russian War Relief, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 221)
    - S (Box 6, Folder 222)
    - Sand, René, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 223)
    - Sarton, George, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 223)
    - Sauerbruch, Ferdinand, 1932, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 224)
    - Schinz, Hans Rudolf, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 225)
    - Senn, Gustav, 1931, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 226)
    - Shryock, Richard Harrison, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 226)
    - Singer, Charles, 1933, 1939, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 227)
    - Singer, Dorothea Waley, (Mrs. Charles), 1939, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 228)
    - Štampar, Andrija, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 229)
    - Stocker, Friedrich, 1941-1947 (Box 6, Folder 230)
    - Subba Reddy, D. V., 1939 (Box 6, Folder 231)